(暗部)敵対する相手が上の場合
質的差を数量で埋めよ。
When facing a higher-skilled opponent...
make up for the difference
in quality with quantity!
あなたから教わった
基本戦術です。
That's the basic battle skills
you taught us.
(ダンゾウ)フッ…
年寄り１人に なんとまぁ…。
How can you do this
to an old man?
そこまで立ててくれるとはのぉ。
I can't believe you'd treat
someone this poorly...
綱手様の命により
あなたを捕縛し➡
On Tsunade-sama's orders,
you are to be captured and
brought back to the Leaf Village.
木ノ葉の里へ連行します。
(暗部)これは…。
(暗部)雨隠れの…。
What's this...?!
He's from the Hidden Rain...
Once I fly,
habataitara
I won't be coming back, I said.
modorena ito itte
And I set out.
mezashita no wa
For that blue, blue sky.
aoi aoi ano sora
I haven't learned "sadness" yet.
kanashimi wa mada oboerarezu
And I'm just starting to grasp "misery".
setsunasa wa ima tsukami hajimeta
Even this feeling I hold towards you.
anata e to idaku kono kanjou mo
Is now turning into "words".
ima kotoba ni wakatteku
Waking up from the dream of this unknown world.
michi naru sekai no yume kara mezamete
I spread these wings and fly.
kono hane wo hiroge tobi datsu
Once I fly,
habataitara
I won't be coming back, I said.
modorena ito itte
And I set out.
mezashita no wa
For that blue, blue sky.
aoi aoi ano sora
Knowing I'll find the answer,
tsuki nuketara
If I pierce through it.
mitsukaru to shitte
if I break free,
furikiru hodo
From that blue, blue sky.
aoi aoi ano sora
Jet-Black Signal Fire
"How To Make Friends"
"Dictionary of Social Relationships"
"How to Become Friends with Strangers"
"If a friend suddenly gets
into a bad mood,
(ナルト)友達が
急に機嫌が悪くなったら…。
"the cause might be due
to changes in eating habits."
原因は 意外に
食生活の変化にあるのかも…。
"Like the color of soba
and udon noodles..."
うどんや そばの色と一緒で…。
I have no idea what
they're talking about!
フンッ… 何言ってるんだか
さっぱり わかんねえってばよ。
Well, neither do I...
(サイ)実は ボクも…。
だよな だよな。
Huh? What? Aren't there like
Cliff Notes or something
もっと簡単に
人の考えが わかるような➡
that explains human thought
in a simpler way?
虎の巻とか ねえのかなぁ。
Sakura-san said I should learn stuff
like this through experience.
サクラさんが そういうことは
経験で覚えろって。
Huh?! Hell no.
え!? イヤだってばよ…。
With him, it'll be a fierce struggle...
I mean... like a wild uproar.
あんな野郎と
くんずほぐれつ… じゃねえ➡
え～と ケンケンガク… ゴ… ガ… ゴ…。
Oh man... Anyway, we'd both go all out
and it'd be really ugly.
いや！ とにかく なんだ その…➡
ガチで つきあうなんてさ。
But I think understanding each other...
でも ナルトとソラなら➡
そういう
ぶつかって わかり合うのが➡
by butting heads would work
for you and Sora.
合ってるんじゃないのかな。
う～ん…。
Well... I'm not really good with stuff like that...
ボクは やっぱ
そういうのが苦手だから➡
もっともっと読まないと。
I have to read more about it.
ふ～ん… よくわかんねえ。
I don't really get it...
ソラのヤツ… ちっとは里に
慣れてきたと思ってたのにな。
That Sora...
And here I thought he was
getting used to things in the village...
What the hell happened to him?
いったい 何があったんだ…。
Danzo-sama...
《ダンゾウ様…》
(綱手)アスマとヤマトは？
Where are Asuma and Yamato?
They have been summoned...
(シズネ)呼んであります。
Explain yourself, Danzo!
(綱手)説明しろ！ ダンゾウ。
Right now, when things are turbulent
at the border with the Hidden Rain,
雨隠れとの国境が
不穏な この時期➡
why was it necessary to go
to the trouble of meeting
なぜ わざわざ危険を冒してまで➡
with a Shinobi from
the neighboring land?
隣国の忍と会う必要があった？
Are you listening?!
聞いているのか！
Wait a minute...
(ヤマト)待ってください…
この男 見覚えがある。
I've seen this man before...!
ボクが暗部にいた頃
任務中 行方不明になった➡
When I was with the Anbu,
he went missing during a mission.
As I recall, his name was... Tatsuji!
確か 名は… タツジ。
So he was the spy Danzo-sama
sent to the Hidden Rain?
(アスマ)コイツ
ダンゾウ様が雨隠れに送り込んだ➡
草だったのか。
(綱手)独断で いろいろと
嗅ぎ回っていたわけか。
So you were sniffing around
on your own, huh?
I don't know what you were looking into
in the Hidden Rain...
(綱手)雨隠れで
何を探っていたかは わからんが➡
つかんだ情報を聞かせてもらおう。
But you will tell me the information
you know.
Was the Hidden Rain involved
with the previous attack?
先の襲撃に
雨隠れは絡んでいるのか？
(ダンゾウ)クッ クッ クッ クッ…。
I can't believe you haven't
even figured that out yet...
その程度の情報すら
集まっていないとはな。
Princess Tsunade,
your conservativeness is fine with me...
綱手姫…
穏健派を気取るのは結構だが➡
But such complacency
will destroy this village!
その油断が里を滅ぼすぞ。
クッ… はなから語る気はないか…。
So you had no intention of talking
from the start, huh...?
いいだろう。 ならば…。
(ダンゾウ)やめておけ。
Very well. If that's the case...
Don't bother...
Do you think he'll talk?
コヤツが
口を割るとでも思っているのか？
フッ… やりようは いろいろあるさ。
There are many ways to do this...
(イビキ)お呼びですか？ 五代目。
You summoned me, Fifth?
I'm counting on you, Ibiki.
頼んだぞ イビキ。
Please leave it to me.
In just ten minutes I'll get him to talk.
お任せください。
10分もあれば
口を割らせてみせます。
Tsunade... Why are you losing your patience?
(ホムラ)綱手… 何を あせっておる？
A Hokage is supposed to
act more dignified.
火影たるもの
もっと どっしり構えておれ。
(ホムラ)
イビキまで引きずり出しおって➡
And you even dragged Ibiki into this.
駆け引きとしても いただけぬな。
This is unacceptable...
even as a strategy.
Now, now... we'll handle this.
(コハル)よしよし… 苦労をかけたな。
Danzo, Tatsuji wasn't just your spy.
ダンゾウ…
タツジは お前だけの草ではない。
He was sending us information
as well...
同時に
我々にも情報を流しておる。
(コハル)ホッ ホッ ホッ ホッ…。
He's a fellow member of the Leaf...
He is not a double spy.
同じ木ノ葉同士じゃ…➡
二重スパイとは言うまい。
(ホムラ)報告によると
今回の国境の襲撃に➡
According to the report,
the Hidden Rain was not involved
with the border attack.
雨隠れは かんでおらぬ。
More importantly, according to Tatsuji,
it seems he was assigned the other day
それより タツジの話では➡
先日 火ノ寺付近の隠し墓を
あばいたと思われる➡
on a mission to track and
monitor the group of four...
thought to be the ones who violated
the hidden tombs near the Temple of Fire.
４人組を追跡。
看視の任務にあたったそうだ。
Then...
それでは…。
お前たちが危惧したように➡
Just as you all feared,
it seems those four were trying
to get their hands on...
その４人は 火ノ寺の あの少年➡
that Sora boy from the Temple of Fire.
ソラを手に入れようと
しておったそうだ。
Tsunade, you know about
the past incident that boy caused
(ホムラ)綱手… お前も➡
過去に あの少年が
火ノ寺で起こした事件は➡
at the Temple of Fire, don't you?
知っておろう。
Yes.
(綱手)あぁ。
(コハル)理由は わからんが➡
I don't know the how,
but there is no doubt that boy
has some kind of power.
あの少年には 何らかの力が
あると見て間違いない。
Power equivalent to,
if not greater than,
ヤツらが奪った
守護忍十二士の亡骸と同等➡
that of the stolen Guardian
Shinobi Twelves' bodies...
もしくは それ以上のな…。
そのような
得体の知れない危険物を➡
I can't believe you'd invite something
so unknown and dangerous into the village.
里に招き入れるとはな…。
If you're the leader of this village
dedicated to protecting it at all,
仮にも
この里を守護する里長ならば➡
you should make a decision immediately.
早急に決断するべきだろう。
しかし このまま
火ノ寺に戻すわけにもいくまい。
But we can't just send him
back to the Temple of Fire.
ならば 幽閉か…。
Then should we incarcerate him?
No... The source of the disaster
threatening this village
いや… 里を脅かす災厄の芽は➡
must be swiftly dealt with.
根こそぎ摘まねばならん。
抹殺か…。
Extermination...?
((フリド : これが お前の本当の力だ))
This is your true power.
《ソラ : どうして
こう オレ様の力ってヤツは➡
Why is this power of mine
so ostracized?
うとまれる…。
This time... This time...
今度は… 今度は…。
アスマの おっさんよ…》
Old man Asuma...
綱手…
火影である お前が判断しろ。
Tsunade... You're the Hokage,
so you make the decision.
木ノ葉の益をよく考えてな。
Think hard about how
it will benefit the Hidden Leaf.
ことわ…。
(ソラ)離せ！
- I won't...
- Let go!
You jerk...!
(ソラ)この野郎！
離せってんだ お面野郎!!
Let go of me, you masked jerk!
Quiet down!
(卯月)おとなしくしろ！
(綱手)ソラ！
Sora!
(卯月)天井裏に隠れていました。
He was hiding in the back of the ceiling.
Damn it!
クソッ！
冗談じゃねえ！ なにが抹殺だ!!
Not a chance!
Extermination, my foot!
Is my power that much of a nuisance?!
オレの力が
そんなに うっとおしいのかよ!?
You jerks are the same as
the guys at the Temple of Fire!
テメエらも
火ノ寺のヤツらと同じじゃねえか！
お前は災いのタネだ。
ダンゾウ！
You're the seed of disaster.
Danzo!
Damn it! All of you jerks...
クソッ！ どいつもこいつも！
何が仲間だ！ カカシ班だ！
Comrades, my foot!
Forget Team Kakashi!
ソラ…。
Sora...
Are you saying I'm going to be punished
with divine retribution...
ちょっとでも
心を許しちまった このオレに➡
for trusting in people just the tiniest bit?!
罰が当たっちまった
っていうのかよ!?
Be quiet, Sora!
静まれ ソラ！
アスマ！ アンタに聞きたいことがある。
Asuma! I've got something
I want to ask you...
Did you...
オレの…
オレの父さんを殺したのは…。
kill my father?
((元守護忍十二士
裏切り者の… 猿飛 アスマだ))
The former member of
the Guardian Shinobi Twelve,
the backstabber Sarutobi Asuma.
父さんを殺したのは アンタか!?
Are you the one who killed... my father?!
オレだ。
Yes, it was me.
カズマにとどめを…
イヤ 殺したのは… オレだよ。
I'm the one who finished him...
I mean... killed him...
I was the one.
((カズマ : アスマ～！
カズマ～！))
Asuma!
Kazuma!
(ソラ)そういうことかよ…！
I get it now...
(ソラ)グォォ～！
これは…！
What's this...?!
How dare you! How dare you!
How dare you...!
よくも… よくも… よくも!!
Stop!
(卯月)やめろ！
うぉ～!!
Wha--?!
《この右手は…》
That... right hand...
《ソラ… お前の力は いったい…》
Sora...
What the hell is... your power...?
How dare you... kill my father...
(ソラ)よくも… 父さんを！
よくも…！
How dare you...!
うぉ～!!
うぉっ！
大丈夫か？ ソラ…。
You okay... Sora...?
ナルト…。
Naruto...!
テメエ
なに出しゃばってきやがった!?
You jerk! What're you doing sticking
your nose in this?!
ヘヘヘ… お前も言ってたじゃねえか。
You said it, didn't you?
((ソラ : 加勢に来たぞ。
I came to help.
誰も頼んでねえってばよ！
No one asked you.
(でも来ちまったものは
しようがねえ))
As long as I'm here,
I have no choice.
来ちまったものは
しようがねえだろ！
"As long as I'm here,
I have no choice," right?
テメエ！ なぜ ソラを襲う!?
You jerk! Why did you attack, Sora?!
根か…。
The Foundation, huh...?!
(ヤマト)ソラ！
Sora...!
ナルト…。
Naruto...?
大丈夫だってばよ。
I'm okay.
仲間を… オレの父さんを…
お前が裏切った！
You betrayed your comrades...
and my father...
I'll avenge my father!
父さんの敵！
ソラ！
待て！
Sora!
Wait!
あの バカ…。
That idiot...
うっ…。
ナルト！
Naruto...!
((忍僧 : コイツを絶対 外に出すな！
(忍僧)すべての門は閉鎖済みです。
Don't let him get outside
no matter what!
All of the gates have been closed.
よし！ では 破邪の陣で拘束する。
ハーッ！
All right, then restrain him
with the Destruction of Evil Seal!
ぐわぁ～!!
ぐはっ！
無念…
だが この先にある封印鉄壁は➡
This is mortifying...
But no one can destroy
the sealed iron walls up ahead...
何者にも破られは…。
(くっ…！))
What?!
また 同じ夢だってばよ…。
The same dream again...
玉が２つあるから
いけねえんだよ。
It's mistaken because there are two kings...
The Feudal Lord of the Land of Fire...
and the Hokage of the Hidden Leaf...
火ノ国の大名と 木ノ葉の火影…。
玉が２つあれば
必ずや混乱と疑心を招き➡
There will always be chaos
and distrust if there are two kings.
事あるとき判断は遅れ
他国の侵略を許すことになる。
And when anything happens,
decisions will be late and
the invasion of other lands will occur.
カズマの考えは いたってシンプルよ。
Kazuma's notion was very simple.
火ノ国よ １つにまとまろうぜ
ってことだからな。
He just wanted to unify
the Land of Fire as one...
が… カズマが正そうとしていた
２つの玉…➡
And... Kazuma attempted
to set the two kings right...
そのこと自体に
カズマは足元をすくわれた。
But he was tricked by
the very problem itself.
結局 この里の人間は
この里の玉につく。
At the end of the day,
the people of this village will stick
with this village's king.
アスマは 火影を
こっちの玉を選んだ。
Asuma chose the Hokage, this king...
He doesn't understand
why this village can shine...
(フリド)ヤツらは わかっちゃいねえ。
この里が輝ける その理由を。
本当の玉 火ノ国あってこそ
輝けるんじゃねえか。
The true king...
the Land of Fire's king allows it to shine!
(フリド)火ノ国のために…。
All for the Land of Fire...
That was Kazuma's cause.
それが カズマの義だ。
そのためにこそ➡
Isn't that why you were entrusted
with your power from Kazuma...?
お前の力は カズマから
託されたんじゃねえのか？
オレの義は 父さんの復讐だ。
それでもいい。
My cause... is revenge for my father.
That's fine. But look hard
at what's past that.
だが その向こうにあるもんを
見つめろ。
カズマが望む 真の復讐をだ。
At the true revenge Kazuma desires.
(フリド)ともに 行こう ソラ。
カズマの義を成し遂げるのだ。
Let's go together, Sora.
Carry out Kazuma's cause.
さすれば アスマを倒すチャンスなど➡
If you do that, I'll create as many chances
as you need to defeat Asuma.
いくらでも作ってやるよ。
(ソラ)もうひとつの玉…。
The other king...
火影…！
The Hokage...
(チョウジ)ソラ～？ ソラ～！
Sora!
(シカマル)まったく
めんどくせえ野郎だぜ…。
For crying out loud...
What a pain he is...
(キバ)チッ！
ニオイを追うのも ここまでか。
Is this as far as the scent goes...?
Hidden Leaf Hospital
(サクラ)ホント アンタの回復力ときたら
いつもながら感心するわ。
I'm always impressed by
your recuperative strength.
みんなで あちこち捜したのよ。
Everyone looked all over for him.
もう 里には いないのかも…。
He might not be in the village anymore.
いや… オレには まだ アイツが
里にいるような気がするんだ。
No! I get the feeling he's still in the village.
そうね。
Yeah...
(サクラ)それじゃ 今日は
ゆっくり やすんでなさい。
Okay, get some rest tonight.
あぁ。
Right...
《ソラのヤツ…》
That Sora...
このチャクラ…！
This Chakra...?
このチャクラの感じ…。 怒り？
This Chakra sensation...
Rage?
間違いねえ！
No doubt about it...
ソラ…！
Sora...!
ふぅ…。
綱手のばあちゃん！
Grandma Tsunade!
大丈夫か？ ばあちゃん！
あぁ。
You okay, Grandma?!
Yeah...
Sora!
ソラ！
うお～っ！
《綱手 : なんだ!? このチャクラは！》
What's this Chakra...?
No!
やめろ！
邪魔するな！
Stay out of this!
お前 なんで ばあちゃんを!?
You! Why did you try to kill her...?!
Out of my way, Naruto!
どけ～！ ナルト！
綱手様！
Tsunade-sama!
クッ…。
Wait! Sora! Naruto!
待て！
ソラ！ ナルト！
待て！ ソラ！
Wait, Sora!
Young people
iiijii na riyuu
I'll always accept your excuses
issai yurusu jakuhai
I summoned the rescue team too
resukuyuu tai mo yonde oita
So
dakara
Please kiss me please kiss me
puriizu kisu mii purizu kisu mi
All night
all night
The magic of a fallen angel or the silly pranks of a little demon
datenshi no mahou ka koakuma no chachi na itazura
Before it gets boring
tsuman naku nacchau mae ni
go and hurl
soore de houre
The bowling ball
bouringu booru
It's a strange existence
kibutsuhason zai nado
I know it already
shouchi no suke
It looks breakable...
kowaresou de
Clear the way with those sloppy emotions
tocchirakatta kanjou de kirihirake yo
It looks breakable
kowaresou de
(シズネ)おや 珍しいものを
見てらっしゃいますね。
Yet it's not our victory
kowasenai bokura no shouri
まっ たまにはな。
(シズネ)ナルト君から 三代目様まで➡
連綿と続く
師弟の流れってとこですか。
Next Episode
フフ… ん！
これは！
What? The power's out in the village.
(シズネ)あの ご意見番の お二人も➡
I wonder if everyone went out.
昔は ずいぶん
かわいかったんですね～。
That couldn't be. It's a power outage!
どこが！ 全然かわいくないぞ！
Oh man, we're out of luck.
What?! I don't like the dark.
(綱手)見ろ！ このナマイキそうな目
ふてぶてしい面構え！
It'll be okay.
The power will be back on soon.
But it seems to be kind of prolonged,
doesn't it?
まんま
面影が残ってるじゃないか。
Come to think of it,
you could be right.
ア アハハ…。
あっ！
What do you think, Konohamaru?
I've got a bad feeling about this...
なぁ そういや アイツの昔って➡
Huh?
And things are really helter-skelter
in the village right now.
どんなんだろうな？
(シズネ)アイツ？
I hope something strange isn't going on.
Lockdown of Darkness
(綱手)ダンゾウだよ。
Next time: "Lockdown of Darkness"
(シズネ)え～っ！
いや マズイですよ 綱手様！
な～に かまうもんか！
ちょ… 綱手様！
Oh, you're looking at
something unusual.
あった～！ これだ～！
Well, once in a while,
you know.
よし いくぞ…。
The group of masters and pupils from
Naruto back to the Third Hokage?
ぬお～！
あひ～！
Hm?
What's this?!
なんつ～か 思ったより アレだな…。
Even the advisors were quite cute
back in the day, huh...?
What?! They're not cute at all.
Look at these conceited eyes
and the impudent look.
Still looks exactly like it was!
Hey... Come to think of it,
what about him back in the day?
Him?
I mean Danzo.
What?! That's a bad idea,
Lady Tsunade.
What? it's no big deal.
Come on, Tsunade-sama!
"THE FOUNDATION
R&R OUTING
HIDDEN VILLAGE HOT SPRINGS"
I found it! This is it!
All right, here we go.
Whoa!
Yikes!
It's more you know what...
than I thought...